CHRISTIAN VELASQUEZ-JAVIER

(velasqcb@bc.edu)

PhD student in Economics ♥ Boston College, Massachusetts, USA □ +1 857-919-7135

Profile and research interest:

Economist with extensive experience in monetary policy design with an emphasis on macroeconomic modeling and forecasting. My research interests are small open economies, sovereign risk, and the macroeconomics of climate change. Highly responsible, pragmatic, and with a broad vision of economic issues.

Education:

- Ph.D. in Economics
 Boston College, Boston (2018 currently)
- M.A. in Economics Boston College, Boston (2018 – 2019)
- BA. in Economics
 Universidad Nacional Agraria La Molina, Lima (2009 2013)

Teaching experience:

- TA of Statistic Lab, Boston College University (Spring 2021)
- TA of Economics Principles, Boston College University (Fall 2020)
- TA of Macroeconometrics, University of Piura (Lima, 2013 2014)
- TA of Financial Econometrics, San Martin de Porres University (Lima, 2014)
- TA of Macroeconometrics, San Martin de Porres University (Lima, 2014)
- TA of Microeconometrics, San Martin de Porres University (Lima, 2013)

Working experience:

- Specialist on Macro modeling
 - Central Reserve Bank of Peru (2015-2018)

Responsible for maintaining, operating, and updating the macroeconomic models used for monetary policy recommendations to the board. Aside, I was in charge of developing and estimating econometric models for short-term forecasting and structural analysis.

- Specialist in Balance of Payment Statistics

Central Reserve Bank of Peru (2013-2015)

Person in charge of compilation, analysis, and reporting of international trade statistics. I was in the team that updated the computing methodology of price indexes and terms of trade.

Training courses:

- Quantitative Methods in Macroeconomics Reserve Bank of Peru, Peru (2017)
- Theory and Application of Dynamic Programming Household Finance and Firm Factor Demand

Reserve Bank of Peru, Peru (2017)

- Monetary and Macroprudential Policies for Small Open Economies Reserve Bank of Peru, Peru (2016)
- Forecasting (and Policy Analysis) with DSGE and Time Series Models Reserve Bank of Peru, Peru (2016)
- VARs for Quantitative Analysis in Central Banking CEMLA, Mexico (2015)
- Macroeconomic Theory with Financial Sector Reserve Bank of Peru, Peru (2015)
- Course of the 6^{th} Manual of Balance of Payment Statistics and International Investment Position CEMLA, Brazil (2014)